Guide to the Ballet Folklorico de Stanford Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ballet Folklorico de Stanford records
1973-2008
1973-1993
SC0901
Ballet Folklorico de Stanford
0.75 Linear feet
Collection includes programs, clippings, correspondence, flyers, and posters, 1974-93 and 2008; photographs, 1973-1992; and DVD copies of filmed performances, 1984-93. The records folder for 1991-92 includes the Twenty Year Commemorative Booklet.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Ballet Folklórico de Stanford was formed in the early 1970s to present and promote Mexican culture to the Stanford campus. Originally affiliated with the academic Dance Division, it is now a student run organization. In addition to the annual El Concierto de la Primavera, the group performs at other campus functions.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes programs, clippings, correspondence, flyers, and posters, 1974-93 and 2008; photographs, 1973-1992; and DVD copies of filmed performances, 1984-93. The records folder for 1991-92 includes the Twenty Year Commemorative Booklet.
Access Terms
Ballet Folklorico de Stanford; Folk dancing--Mexico.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 2008 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Photographs
  - 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Audiovisual materials, 1984-1993
  - Cinco de Mayo, 1984; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Concierto de la Primavera, 1985; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Concierto de la Primavera, 1987; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Concierto de la Primavera, 1988; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Concierto de la Primavera “Salsa Chicana”, 1990; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Ballet Folklorico “Crossing Borders”, 1990; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Concierto de la Primavera, 1991; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Concierto de la Primavera Carnavel en Veracruz, 1992; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Concierto de la Primavera 20th Anniversary, 1993; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)